Daniel Pinedo

□+1 213-999-5619 | **S** daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu | **A** pinedo.org

Introduction __

I have extensive experience as a statistician, data scientist, evaluation scientist, university lecturer, and organizational psychologist.

My background and experience has varied over the years from IT network administration and management to most recently Global HR consulting and analytics and data science support for program evaluation. I delight equally in employee relations, learning and development, crunching numbers, and consulting with and advising global leaders.

I am highly proficient in presenting and lecturing; and using the reporting tools Excel, Tableau, Power BI, R, and Python.

Education ___

Claremont Graduate University

Claremont, CA

MA Psychology

Sep 2018 - May 2020

• Concentrations in Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

Sofia University

Palo Alto, CA

MA Psychology

Sep 2010 - May 2013

Concentration in Clinical Psychology

Naropa University

Boulder, CO

BA TRADITIONAL EASTERN ARTS

Sep 2008 - May 2010

• Student Government: Treasurer

Professional Experience _____

| Sep 2019 - Mar 2022 | Principal, Kinesis Consulting (20 hours / | week) |
|---------------------|---|---------|
| SCP ZOIS Mai ZOZZ | i inicipat, rancois consulting (20 nours) | vvccity |

Nov 2018 - Jun 2020 Consultant, Accenture Plc, CGU Talent Innovation Lab (20 hours / week)

Sep 2016 - May 2018 Lecturer, Psychology, Mount Saint Mary's University (full time)

Aug 2014 - Jul 2015 Clinician, Sovereign Health Group, adult partial inpatient rehabilitation center (full time)

Aug 2013 - Jul 2014 Clinician, Mind Body Awareness Project, adolescent drug and alcohol counseling (20 hours / week)

Aug 2012 - Jul 2013 Clinician, San Mateo County juvenile detention center, forensic psychological evaluation (20 hours / week)

Aug 2011 - Jul 2012 Clinician, Lifemoves family homeless shelter, individual & family therapy (20 hours / week)

2002 - 2008 IT Consultant, network engineering specialist (full time)

Evaluation

Kinesis ConsultingPhoenixville, PAROLE: PRINCIPALSep 2019 - present

• Statistical consultation including social science methodology, visualization, and presentation in support of policy & planning analysis and program evaluation for the scientific community. Focus is on methodological innovation for evaluation in support of climate change mitigation and resilience infrastructure projects. Examples of recent projects:

- Survey analysis and presentation for external program evaluation in NSF Directorate for Geosciences
- Mixed method / Social network analysis for external program evaluation in NSF Division of Undergraduate Education
- Social network analyses for external program evaluation in NSF Office of Integrative Activities.

Consulting _____

Accenture Talent Innovation Lab

Claremont, CA

Nov 2018 - Jun 2020

ROLES: CONSULTANT, PROJECT MANAGER, TEAM LEAD

- Global HR / Recruitment Transformation Research & Development Lab
- Managed project deliverable content and translated research into business cases.
- Consulted with stakeholder managers on organizational behavior, management, statistics, research methods, interviewing, and focus groups.
- · Led project teams.
- Managed performance and career development.
- Managed project timelines, milestones, personnel time, and budgeting.
- Trained team on client on-boarding, acculturation, pitching and public speaking, time management, technical mentoring, and cross-functional communication.
- Created interviewing/hiring criteria as member of Recruitment and Selection Committee.
- Served as resource for strategy insights and revenue ideas.
- High-impact project examples include:
 - Future workplace job redesign research and market analysis for account executive role
 - Documentation sprint to prepare final presentation of vetted global employee selection and assessment model
 - Validation of scoring measure for behavioral interview
 - Development of values-based assessment prototype
 - Selection assessment design prototype
 - Leadership model synthesis and design

Claremont Graduate University

Claremont, CA

Sep 2018 - May 2020

DEPT OF BEHAVIORAL AND ORGANIZATIONAL SCIENCES

- Evaluation plan for North America regional HR client organization Arup
- Intensive organizational behavior assessment center for Getty Leadership Center
- · Organizational culture project for private, family-owned property management firm
- Organizational behavior project for ICM Partners creative talent agency undergoing HR restructuring
- Competition: BCG Datathon team leader for invitation only data science business case competition

Professional Development_

2020 - 2021 Data Scientist with Python, Certificate

DataCamp

Data Scientist with R, Certificate

Data Visualization with R. Certificate

Designing and Analyzing Clinical Trials in R, Certificate

Machine Learning Scientist with Python, Certificate

Machine Learning Scientist with R, Certificate

Network Analysis with R, Certificate

R Programmer, Certificate

Shiny Fundamentals with R, Certificate

Spatial Data with R, Certificate

Survival Analysis in R, Certificate

Statistician with R, Certificate

Time Series with R, Certificate

2021 Certified Six Sigma Black Belt, Certificate

Six Sigma Academy Amsterdam